and we are live and somehow I feel like
this is like when you and like volunteer
and everyone steps backwards and you're
standing there
everyone muted is cuz you had lives so
clearly we'd be intro this so this is
our roundtable we do this every Saturday
morning we get together to say what our
project is or what we've done on our
project everyone's probably pretty first
on our projects maybe not mine because
it changes every week but the wiki
election and recent score I think are
fairly concrete things that people think
get their heads around yeah so welcome
to the roundtable who wants to actually
start the day well I can go ahead and
start so yeah project I guess we should
do a short spiel each time per project
is reason score it's a collaborative
decision-making tool that's based on
evidence rather than opinion so instead
of voting you add facts so oh it's still
kind of so this last week I've spent a
lot of time on it and now that I've quit
my job and working full time actually
like 60 hours when I which it just seems
crazy a couple times I woke up at 3:00
a.m. thinking about it worked on it so
and so I'm making a lot of progress but
I'm having to redo them the math again
because I'm figuring some things out
it's you know since I'm doing something
no one's ever really done before it's
it's not like I can write a spec and
code it I have to figure it out as I go
an experiment so that's what I've been
up to I guess I don't know I guess I
said last time I was working on some
visualizations way to show that where
the debate is and stuff I'm so I'm gonna
keep working on that and then in this
coming week gosh I don't know what I'm
gonna do I've try and finalize the math
and get it to where I want to be able to
show how each fact impacts the whole
debate right now it's kind of abstract
and you have to think it through okay
that's true and then it's here and so I
want to
make it more intuitive so once I have
the numbers then I can work on the user
experience so yeah that's my update
coolie I guess all the next so Adriel
with wiki election here wiki election is
not very dissimilar to reason score it
is meant to be an information platform
centered around science politics and
news and similar to recent score it's
based on evidence in this case but with
an emphasis on sort of a library of
experts that would review the events and
then you can compare their reviews to
what we know about them how skilled they
are any conflict of interest that kind
of thing last Saturday I did a I guess a
tour of the expected features before the
part for politics with Susan Kosh and it
went quite well so I will be updating
some of the the content and sort of I
guess making some improvements based on
that feedback if you want to add what
these go ahead but so I did the live
stream I updated the content I'm also
working on water frames because unlike
Bettany I'm not a programmer so I'm
gonna have to hire one and so I'm
working on respect so that I can
actually give that to someone to start
coding an early version of it something
else that I was going to say but I'm
forgetting sold is called there you like
to go bet lays already gone I haven't
gone yet I can go either although and
then you can have a moment yeah throw
you in the deep end so I am Jubilee part
of together Tech which is this as well
as solution raising or we have an
hour-long conversation generating ideas
we can actually implement now with
10,000 people and $100,000
and then also this newer project which
is this five questions which I've been
talking a lot of people about which is
becoming kind of my version of the
religion that's not a religion that
answering these five questions is in no
way
I don't I don't need you to answer them
my way it's about how you answer them
and just answering them themselves is is
beneficial to yourself and society so
this last week I have held the solution
raising on Wednesdays that I do live at
8:30 in the morning we did it on
materials and packaging this week we're
gonna be doing it on the meta-crisis
just how all the crisises are
intertwined and how if you fix one the
other other ones break and like how you
actually deal with that the derrick
wanting to talk about it's definitely
under up my alley and then the five
questions I'm just answering I do my
8:30 broadcast before this and I'm just
answering those five questions which are
like Who am I who are my people what is
my purpose what do I need and the fifth
question that was added last week is
what am I ready to let go of and which
can be in those other four and so that
is that is what I'm up to and although I
don't think you'd roll an Bentley did it
this time um I asked what I would love
to universe to give me or a student
during this hour is what I have for the
last few weeks which is people to
co-create a process with to go from ID a
problem through solution to actually
creating it into the world and what that
can look like in our current world and
then that process is iterative and of
course keeps improving
so people who that's their jam who they
want to have conversations about
conversations conversations about the
system and the participation itself and
how that can be fun and easy for the
individual and be the world powerfully
so that is my update okay so my biggest
I am on Facebook and I've been busy with
these past few days the new group called
mapping and we had and sorry about this
today and the other I think they didn't
know that this meeting is happening is a
philistine time so it just happened it
was second meeting of this kind of the
continuation of the meeting from
Thursday and it was about creating but
initially I expected narrow scope of how
to
create a tool that maps relations and
entities in v9b space which is what I am
after turned out that it was much much
broader than this and we discussed
everything education economics and
technical side of it which is what's the
benefit of 3d space and how 3d space and
visualization is better than just to die
nationals and possibly four dimensions
it's even better because of the timeline
and you can see how things change in
time not only in space and how to create
that and what needs to go inside and
generally yeah yesterday's meeting took
three hours and stopping the first
meeting as well so it's like six hours
of recording interval hunter who's the
instigator of promised to post it
somewhere and I'm not sure if it
happened but it surely will and it was
very interesting and it is going to
happen again next week hopefully so yeah
and myself I'm busy creating something
very apart from that first project I
worked on which was meeting scheduler
which got to a certain point and then I
got distracted and then I got back to
something older that I was trying to do
because of being inspired by all the
other people who want to do the same
thing which is basically to create a
tool to hello to to map stuff
and I am no different so I create my own
version of it which at some point I am
totally happy to show and me predict all
what it is and why it's not something
better and yes that's basically me
right so on and off Ramon's gonna come
back in or not but we could probably go
ahead and so the format we kind of
discussed with this was that we would do
our low-end shows and then we someone
takes the hot seat and we you know try
and help them with any issues they have
or anything they want to do does anyone
have a driving desire to be on the hot
seat this week anyone have any needs I
just can't think of what topic I would
be in thought c4 so I'm totally done
with anyone being in the hot seat but if
anyone has ideas on how I find people to
work through the process with I would
also be okay with being in the hot seat
because anyone could I'll be with that
or other people yeah so that is more
than just building an audience that's
specifically just getting people who
want to participate in those settings on
video yeah okay yeah particularly people
who just like we are concentrated on
like creating the tech itself in like
our own projects and doing that and
we've a meeting for this process really
it's like people who want to have the
conversation about the process so it's
not all on me as far as like the
solution area scene I'm fine with the
hour-long conversation we're doing at
the same time people show up they show
up we have a conversation if not I don't
know what's gonna happen but yeah
finding two or three other people who
want to have a weekly conversation on
process how do we go from creating what
could a process look like with ten
thousand people that it looks doable
right now right that's probably gonna
look like a show or a voting system
something that is participatory but not
this participatory right like a tiny
group to do this and then other people
to watch it or like the zoom having had
it like
what those differences concentric
circles are right like the 10,000
contributing of money how many of those
people want to be the conversation and
be more intuitive are those with one do
the actual work and volunteer and
collect the data and implement how many
those people want to be like right you
know full-time job or something but like
people who wanted to start a
conversation just a conversation here
so as I'm understanding right you're
wanting I just had this boss that tray
about my people what do I find people
how do I find people where do I find
people right now it's a Facebook group
and in our long conversations 8:30 to
9:30 on Wednesday which is the solution
raising itself and I would like to have
another one like another week at 8:30 in
the morning because it seems to take one
of the other days of the week to meet
and have hey how do we actually move
this word I don't have a solution
raising on solution raising and I would
love people who want to continually be
involved right like this is their thing
too but even if it's just like with this
ocean racing one-off people to cotton to
have a solution I I think that would be
great to tackle that but maybe sense
Raymond joined us we should let him I
don't know Raymond if you know the the
format on doing a little intro do you
want me to let you know what that is or
yeah please sorry I'm not be done any
and definitely don't have to participate
so but if you want to this is it follows
the kind of standard mastermind hot seat
format so everyone comes on gives a good
big quick intro on what their project is
since we're doing this live on video
that people might so they have some
context and then kind of what you've
done next last week and then kind of
what you want what you want to do next
week on your project kind of is
accountability
and then we'll do someone as a hot seat
Jib you know which is a person that that
everyone would focus on for the rest of
the meeting and that's just a loose
format we don't have to stick to it so
yeah so if you want to kind of share
what you're working on then we'd be
happy to have you do that okay thanks
yeah I'm working on the the meta guests
of the medi of meta e of protocols right
so we talk about solution building for
solution building I used a different
word but it was great um you know that's
really I was on the holo chain cord dev
team anyone familiar with hole a chain
on its claw yeah so I stumbled into that
because that's what I needed to build
what I want to build which I've
ultimately called protocol that love and
it is basically the encouragement of
vulnerable transparency in all aspects
of our social coordination and
interpersonal sure to the extent that
that you that you embody vulnerable
transparency and your interpersonal in
your way of being that's all fuelling
you fueling us all to be in better
relationship socioeconomically all that
love just kind of answers the question
what would we want to know about
organizations doing work in the world
what are all the questions that we want
to have answers to live real-time for
full transparency and then proposes a
protocol on what the format that the
holo chain protocol means by which that
could be recorded on distributed ledger
technology for all posterity and
something I've been working on for I
don't know three or four or five years
depending on how you look at the various
levels of ramping up but when I tried to
build things on the theory and smart
contracts as a theorem smart contracts
in 2014 I realized that we have
scalability issues there so I ended up
finding holo chain and they asked me to
join the core dev team so I did that and
that proved to be a very amazing
experience to work with some really
really smart people and get to
participate in the ICL which which I can
in theory right I'm supposed to be able
to find this whole thing provide the
mechanism for everybody to to you know
take on accountabilities work out of
their house you know do things what
really feels good did the Akagi if you
will say or where all the things are in
alignment something you love doing
something the world needs something that
you're good at and something that you
can get paid for if you can everybody
can find that in the world that's my
dream world I want to live in it's what
I want for myself the thing is I've left
I kind of I'm a left
a game a reject and I've been working
with mostly game a rejects for a long
time meaning either game a rejected me
or I rejected game a or bulk pretty
consistently through my whole life and
I'm about as old as you can beat it I
think experienced something like that
and still but still hat but I had the
opportunity to be in tech so it's always
been easy to to find some way to to get
by but it's good to be have found my way
into groups like this where there's a
lot of more academic scientific stable
consistent minds that haven't been like
really traumatized by game a so much I
think it's a little it's a it's a good
invite I'm excited to be moving into
those those fields of when I talk about
this stuff I don't know if I was
supposed to have a timeline but I'm
trying to wrap up so last week I'm
really in team-building mode right now
the budget is low because although Jane
is supposed to launch like a year and a
half ago and I was supposed to get
access to the rest of my funding we are
way way way behind schedule
I can talk about lots of details around
that I said what's that I think we just
had a bit of that cocoa they don't
finish up yeah I but the rest is coming
the rest of the the investment I made
through my participation on the team it
should be a town soon as when holo
launches
and yes so I'm really in team-building
mode really putting together primarily a
consulting agency but it's it's all
gifted right now and for the foreseeable
future I want it to be where we can just
teach people how to set up your
organizations in a game be structure
protocol that love proposes all the
means by which from the day you start
talking about doing something seriously
here's how you start those conversations
here's how you have those conversations
here's how you align all the dynamics
around power and money and all the
things that destroy organizations
eventually if those things aren't made
clear or at least feelings get hurt and
people get tossed aside who contributed
and end up with nothing things like that
all these patterns these these could
I've been involved in tech startups and
activist startups for 15 years or so so
I see the same power and Diet power and
money dynamics destroy amazing project
after amazing project or or that not
destroy the project but the project will
ultimately have some level of success
but there's people who contributed in
big ways they got left along the highway
so that's what I want to see and then
protocol that love is else is the URL
and also I did a sit it's called teapot
sauna which is a form of Vipassana that
was very enlightening for me a really
life-changing experience coming out of
that I really channeled the whole new
approach to talking about this in terms
of love versus control and I have an
article on medium it's it's been getting
pretty I was surprised at the
distribution it got and I would love to
share that with you guys to to see some
of the philosophy behind all this
thank you I hope that didn't take too
long but I appreciate what this group is
doing look forward to learning more
about all your projects and seeing how
we get the play that's good and do you
also if you have any requests that we
can help you with
right now just well sure I mean just
generally getting up to speed and giving
feedback is really it I mean I'm looking
for you know I people read the stuff and
I get lots of positive kudos but nobody
says I haven't had anybody criticize
anything yet oh yeah we're yeah yes no
like well this isn't this isn't going to
work
because of this or you know so I've got
a lot of detailed plans laid out so
definitely share that in the Facebook
group and asked for criticism and I'm
sure several of us on here would be
happy to to see if we could provide any
value to you and feedback that's my Jim
I love her what are reading people's
like world-changing idea and then if I
have to stay all positive it doesn't
work it's like I want to be curious I
want to like well this one about this so
if you want to set up a chat later in
the week or next week and and after I've
looked over it I would I would love to
do that with you and it sounds like
we're in the same um skier there's
probably before you popped on where
you're having some tech difficulties my
task when I was gonna possibly in the
hot seat I think you could actually help
but that you might have people that are
that are involved that would be in my
alignment but right now let's introduce
the person can join let him say his name
I can't even read my brother's name
barely so well let well let you
introduce yourself and say you can hear
me yes hello everyone thank you for
having me here actually to be honest
with you I just jumped in I found out
about this like three four minutes ago a
friend of mine a colleague you know
invited me to this event he said that I
should be here because what I'm working
on is very similar so what I think
Bentley and atria like can't even
remember exactly who he said so I'm just
I'm just here because I got the call
real quick I'll tell you what I'm doing
and that you want to hear more basically
it's it's big this is because there are
so many ways to defray miss it's a
political party but it's it's an ape
it's a nonpartisan political party
because it actually represents a whole
new system of democracy and the party is
called the International logic party it
does not stand for any ideas and it
never will
instead it we use this new networking
platform called Agora at the worldwide
stock market of ideas for each person to
build their own political philosophy out
of different ideas to show which ideas
are most strongly supported by the
people and then the cross-reference the
idea
dominance index the people's individual
ideological profiles to create a list of
political candidates who most closely
represent the will of the people and
there's a whole funding aspect that's
involved is there so much more to this
but but the whole point of this this
system is that we actually use it in our
citizen assemblies it's it's a way of
scaling the dynamics of a citizen
democracy to unlimited size so the way
the way that people use this online
platform is actually ninety percent of
the time is offline discussing those
ideas in the platform with other
people's and meetings but the platform
keeps track of what people think and
yeah and allows people to explore each
other definitely sounds similar yeah
yeah there's some there's some overlap
between our projects and just so we
don't know how do you say your first
name it says on it says all right catch
everybody thank you well real quick I
just did it I would I wouldn't introduce
you with the One Nation people but I see
you already know them so that's great
I'd love to find out what that
collaboration looks like well that's how
I met Darryl Kuehl well then we finally
have introductions out of the way so I
kind of propose that we kind of
brainstorm around jubblies idea
I don't think 30 minutes worth it I
think we'll have a little time left over
to handle any other aspects as well so
for people who don't know I'm doing a
update again solution raising is a
hour-long conversation we've had about
nine or ten of them on various topics of
the economy so we spend an hour talking
we spend 15 minutes of the hour talking
about what that it looks like in that
current space which is where we spend on
nearly a hundred percent of our time in
the regular world right complaining
about what what is that we then switch
over to which is why it's only 15
minutes then we spend 15 minutes talking
about what each of us would love to see
in the future like our ideal version of
that
future they don't need to match and then
we spent half an hour talking about what
we could actually create now if we had
10,000 people at $100,000 what is
something that would that would help
move this problem powerfully forward for
those 10,000 people and what I'm looking
for those conversations are fun and
they're great I want to actually have a
group of people to be able to have
solution ratings on social reasons
itself how do we get what does the
process look like with 10,000 people and
that's where it evens I was like yes all
about the money and the power and those
dynamics and that kind of stuff too is
like the idea of raising it from the
bottom is that the more people feel
they're involved in it the more they're
willing to put up with with risks like
real risk in that vulnerability and that
transparency of like oh wait this isn't
going right we don't have enough money
how do we get more money and doing that
so I'm looking for a few people who want
to meet weekly to talk about to either
have a either a one-off solution raising
on solution raising is like the bare
minimum I want and but what I would love
is a group of people who are willing to
meet every week for an hour to have the
conversation about what does that look
like to create with 10,000 people what
could it look like and then start and
actually prove the process
so they wouldn't have any suggestions
and jublee just to be clear you I mean I
know of several like tools and stuff to
kind of help build those or processes to
look at but you're specifically looking
for people that are interested to kind
of go through that process with you so
yeah and tools are great but it like
everything I think white is the tool you
need 100% right so it's about like what
is the process look like and then if we
have 10,000 people we can create our own
tool that's not a problem it can be
perfect for what we need it to be in the
kitchen we improve it's about like how
can we use zoom and Facebook and the
things that already exist how do we have
a TV show of the 10,000 people watch
like what as one of the 10,000 what
would we want it to be as one of the you
know five that are in the center what do
we want it to be like just having those
conversations and creating creating that
so that then there is a way to create
something because once there's a way to
create something with 10,000 people and
$100,000 then we can do it in every
single sector and continually keep
improving all of them and creating it
together so that's what what I'm
focusing on well I have very specific
proposal around something that pretty
much would look good look just like that
and just need to have it torn apart so
that is your okay so yeah perfect which
is my jam having conversations with like
one-off conversations on other people's
projects and my project and our projects
are so in alignment that yes there's no
way something doesn't come out of it
trying to say like that like a troll has
said before like try to fail at not
having any generation come out of that
conversation yeah so I could I could
just give it a really brief overview of
how I see it if you want yeah that's
possible
I'm solutely sure so the object is
certainly like you said to have it come
or originate from the bottom up and like
so so individuals and individual ideas
would present their ideas they we create
an environment they can form teams
around those ideas I do that I have a
process
something I call collective foundational
document it's not quite a process right
it's a protocol it's
protocol that love defines the output
you would want from that process that
you can record on the holo chains but
the process to get there isn't my
specialty I've been well I've been I've
walked many many groups through a
process but it is by no my I am by no
means like a group facilitator super
empathic kind of space holder guy but
the groups but so from from individual
ideas something like like something like
almost what you're doing here with
individual pitches kind of like give
give minute pitches let's decide what we
want to work on let's decide how who was
interested in working with you
permanently let's help you do collect
the foundational document let's get that
registered on the protocol that love
browsers what I would see it as right
it's just this rat browser that you can
give it holo train app addresses and it
can it'll it'll eventually crawl and
find all the connections between all the
organizations and all the people and all
the things for anybody using protocol
dot love so you get it reg it's
registered there so people can find you
and then the the plan everything you do
is completely transparent every single
decision that gets made every currency
transaction everything I propose is
based on different concepts of
currencies which are just metrics in the
flow of exchange and we get to see all
that and we see what's working this is
very much about ultimately identifying
the type of ways people are working
together that are proving to have the
most positive impact and what is
positive impact we don't even get it
like if we even tried to centrally
determine what positive impact I think
we're we're going down a game a type
Road right everybody is to talk about
what impact is for them as well what
does impact mean to me well I can create
a currency that identifies impact that I
see other organizations or people have
any and I can assign that to their
digital ID now if I'm the only one who
is who cares about that particular
impact then it's not gonna mean much in
the world but if it but if it turns out
that other people are saying yeah that
I'm being impacted in that way I think
that's an important flow to use then
these these impact currencies start to
have some meaning in the world's and so
everything is completely organic and of
course the ultimate of that is whole a
chain which is by nature unenclosed well
meaning it cannot be centralized like
like even Bitcoin in a theory ml ds1
watching projects the miners actually do
control the blockchain and so right now
if the three biggest Bitcoin mining
networks merged they would control the
Bitcoin blockchain of course I'm sure
there'd be some backlash and that
wouldn't last long but the point is it
is centralized abaut it is controllable
despite what everybody would type is
that despite what it towns so wholly
change solve that problem by it and also
solve the scalability issues and the the
power consumption issues and everything
all along the way and that essentially
they did by looking at how nature works
in terms of information storage and not
not how computer systems behind data
walls work which is the way we've done
everything so far since the birth of the
internet for last 20 years so it's
completely open environment where
everybody can spawn what's important to
them and then we look for the
connections and then you know things
certain projects should take on a life
ecosystems should form relationships
between entities should form central
governance may form at various levels
where there's versus completed complete
agreement from the various entities
that's with let's watch all that
happened let's get let's let's see what
people actually do when they're actually
free to do whatever to form a society
however they want anyway I rambled on
but that sounds like some exciting stuff
down line I was writing notes cuz I just
had a conversation I missed this last
Saturday um because I don't know who
dropped up just like oh he left on
purpose I was like wait what's going on
um having oh that the the thing I've
missed for last time was talking to
someone from the DAO stack about their
project the common coming out that's
about it's because you what you just
described is concentrating on the output
and then you're forming it around it and
there's just concentrated on the problem
that you're then constant it's like
they're actually very different but some
very similar at the same time and so
it's great because there you can
depending on your personality which one
you want you want to concentrate around
the outcome or do you want to
concentrate around the problem and I'm
concentrating on the process of how do
you actually create something with
10,000 people what can that look like
without having the tech capability and
so that there are these powerful things
in the pipe
coming down the line because like
everything's possible once we have that
technology and enough people to create
projects with right so I'm very excited
that it happens and like I said let's
set up a chance to talk about and I'll
have a chance to look at the protocol
dot love and I'm getting more and more
excited about hollow chain and Dow staff
just existing which yeah yeah yeah we're
closely I'll stack guys and that's an
interesting it's an interesting approach
like the way you're looking at I like
that and the other thing I want to say
is yeah like the the the fact that we
don't need any tech tools right now
vulnerable transparency something we can
embody now we don't need any tools and
that's what I really love about the
approach I'm taking because the second
we have a tool into the I name kind of
data wall or even on you know aetherium
to a much lesser extent but yes we are
off we are off and running and we I want
to be able to build interfaces for the
organizations as they need them great
perfect thank you
so I think what I'm I'm okay of some
well so sig hot see what I plan on doing
for the next week is I'm gonna write up
something for the game be regular
Facebook page asking like hey here's the
time I want to do it is there anyone
else available who wants to be and I'm
also gonna set up a time to meet with
Raymond's I think there's and I want to
do that first I should want to have the
conversation with you first because I
feel like that's more generative of um I
don't know like I feel like something
will come out of it but then I can write
up and put the game be and ask an actual
ask of like there's the time here's the
space here's what we're doing who wants
to come and participate again as a
one-off or weekly I'll try the weekly
then if I don't get bite if I got
crickets I'll try one off and welcome
shiloh do you want to give your update
for today or you can just jump in when
you feel like it either work I have
another call I'm waiting for but I was
listening in and I was just wondering
for one thing is that motika yes and I
was listening about your call yesterday
yes what you're mapping cross ended
really
and I was wondering if it was recorded
and yes yes hunter did record everything
about 10 minutes of the second meeting
and he promised online somewhere which I
don't think it already did with anybody
in the conversation from Halloween no
just mapping brain and I think both the
brain who we are a and the other brain
so a bunkie okay um Raymond I love what
you're saying I'm really interested in
poaching and how well they can map
things especially this connectivity so I
was wondering if maybe you comment on
that how your how hollow chain actually
is a way of mapping and maybe I'm
totally wrong but I feel like it's the
best so far making connections and
showing the connectivity of different
things but also being decentralized not
through a mean count and I will mute the
hollow chain is a fully distributed
application development ecosystem so it
uses BitTorrent technology ultimately to
store data so all the notes have little
bits and pieces of the data all
throughout the network it's not any one
central place and there is no one
central ultimate version of the data at
all every every node has a different
version of the data a different view on
data just like it is in nature
einsteinium reality you know so but we
it's really easy just like we all have
100% different view of the universe we
can build consensus around all kinds of
things and that's the way nature works
and we nature deals with information so
information that's not accessed as much
gets put way back in a corner of our
brain or of our species brain and when
we need access it is
there and we can pull it out um so
that's exactly the way holder chain
works and that bit then again that
protocol has been being designed being
operating successfully for 20 solid
years on BitTorrent but so now we can
take database application databases
right live real-time application
databases and have them stored on a
BitTorrent type protocol so in terms of
so it's the ultimate meta there is no
you so you could be running a holo chain
app across the internet with you and
your friends and nobody else would even
know it exists really have any way of
finding it exists unless they have a
really sophisticated packet sniffer on
really big pipes um you know they could
they could see oh that's a whole chain
protocol we'd said we saw that and that
nodes talking that node now you can map
it out but so the trick with things like
registries and directories and things is
you have to have a central about a seis
decentralized centralized you know
registry and so somebody could create
that somebody could say hey I so in
other words protocol that love will
probably participate like as an
organization they were in helping
registries exist for people who want
their organization and they're
vulnerable transparency of their
organization to be known to the world
but I hope that answered the question
yeah I think so it's hard it's such a
deep expansive topic to talk about the
way it's just so broad and it can have
so many different ways to do it just
like keep hearing it over and over and
over helps and I wanted to say hi this
is Ari I'd seen him before on radish 24
I think the 24 hour black party so hi
this is Ari
Thank You Raymond
I just wanted to ask where do we get
10,000 people and I'm asking
specifically because I know there are
tens of thousands of people interested
in in broadly speaking in what we are
interested in as in fixing the world and
stuff and and now they seem to be
working in groups and they hear about
themselves and each other they are
mostly aware of each other existence but
not necessarily willing to work together
to create something like one even to
create a network of exchange of
information and possibly value so this
is what I be seeing for fast I'm not
sure how many years I've been looking at
this this space which now we can call
game B others yeah lots of people and
lots of groups but not a lot of
cooperation between them so I'm really
curious if the protocol that this can
somehow change and can proactively go
out and connect forcefully if need be
but just connect everyone together so at
least they are fully aware of the big
picture instead of like for example the
Venus Project is doing nothing there is
the zeitgeist movement a slightly
different based on the same idea but
yeah but given how many people and
groups would like to do something and
how little is actually done so connect
yeah that's absolutely the problem I've
been said how to solve cuz you know I've
been involved in The Venus Project since
way back in the day and all the other
groups and things like that I'm living
in an intentional community now I can
salt with intentional communities I'm
designing their organizations in this
way and I'm building you know I buy what
I'm doing in the world is building a
network of intentional communities and a
fleet of vehicles to move goods and
people between them and protocols out
love and some kind of tech is also a
necessary step for that so the idea is
definitely bringing vulnerable
transparency and so I touched on
something there which was by force you
know I obviously if we started we did
say that anyway we're back to game a so
there's this so vulnerable transparency
is always always a choice and it always
takes extra effort really and so there's
nothing we could ever do to stop people
from not being from resisting vulnerable
transparency like there will be many
people who in many organizations who
resist it for various reasons I don't
know well I don't even know all the
reasons right but it's one second we
become punitive about that game over
game B ended we just went back to game a
so it's like it's like it should be
here's my theory is that if we get
enough data into the holo chains right
we can actually do analysis on that data
and we can algorithmically identify
rival risk behavior and if we see the
reverse behavior happening we can say
hey so this is not working as
efficiently for you guys even the
rivalry sectors you're actually not
winning as big as you could be winning
if we created it all win for everybody
else and like if we if we actually have
the data to identify that and somebody
can just write write the algorithm that
solves it why would anybody say no I
mean so that's that's the theory of the
game be perfect world right which i
think is like it's like how to find the
first 10,000 and we are fractured all
over the place and I think that's
exactly how it's supposed to be right
now like there isn't Dow stock and holo
chain aren't supposed to come together
and create one right now they're
supposed to and no not really you don't
like the fact that they exist separately
is is it it fractures the people
involved but it gives us resiliency in a
different way if one of them Falls we
have the other
and advice first if there's any one's
coming out as well at a point I think we
come together at a point it doesn't make
it when you see that data that our
disconnection costs us efficiency and
costs us something then we come together
but how do we find 10,000 people now is
I think you don't need 10,000 people on
Kolodziej turns out stack they need
10,000 people on the products they're
making right on the systems they're
making and so if you're if being
involved at that level like Amazon does
not have a problem finding 10,000 people
Facebook does not have a problem finding
10,000 people so having someone have
like finding 10,000 viewers finding
10,000 customers find that is like the
level of 10,000 I'm looking for and then
how how much do you want to be involved
if someone if 10,000 people are funding
it and co-creating solutions how much
does that co-creation look like for me
it looks like I want to have the
conversations I want to have hours and
hours of conversations if needed so that
that we can get to that but for other
people it's just like yeah so my
education here's $10 no problem and
they're not gonna get they can't then
come back after and be like wait no no
that wasn't what I wanted for the
education right you weren't involved in
it so does that in any way answer your
question like we give them something
from day one and right now it's not for
10,000 people okay just wanted to add
that I would not ever expect for
everything to come together into one
being because that seems to be a mistake
some people of groups make they are
willing to cooperate as long as whoever
joins is going to like wear the same
colors here our values and please come
to us and work together as long as
you're willing to like so no I wouldn't
expect like the whole stock and whole
chain to become one
but cooperation between all the entities
despite the set the exact sets of values
they all adhere to I mean obviously
there are some common values that are
good and and so on
but I wouldn't expect all of the actors
all the actors to be cooperating in the
same direction
yeah I think it's crystal clear and I
can maybe make it clear I think what
you're saying is I write that if for
instance if holo chain decided to that
they wanted to operate completely
transparent transparent sleeve
honourably transparent and they thought
that they could use the owner to do that
they could choose to do that if Dow
stack as an organization wanted to
operate with vulnerable transparency and
shows protocol that love to publish that
vulnerable transparency right that's
we're now we're working together just
like that right I love the competition
councils that's that's exactly what it
is when you identify rivals behavior
like there's nothing wrong with
competition I think that's an
insuperable if we are competing to make
the best I'll win planet for all life
like rock on but the second we get rival
or so we want to win over the other
parties and that's the difference it is
like for me as a user I don't want to
have to login to dowse tax version of
common in your debt your subversion of
this I will in the beginning absolutely
because I care more this exists but I'm
not your average everyday user and so
someone being on one is gonna cost the
other one I think there's ways
centralization feels like the wrong word
but like there's data out there there's
people out there and the more we can
bring those together in a way that feels
safe and usable to the people in the
data like if there's one pool of data
but every project and everyone can use
it because it's decentralized if I'm in
control of that data
no one's gonna trust it no one's gonna
use that as a common place but the more
we have a say in what's happening there
what's stored there what can it be used
for what can then
there's efficiency that isn't quite
competition cooperation and it builds on
itself like you when Dow stack and
hollow chain need to come together they
will come together and otherwise and
they're more likely to come together
than let's say Amazon and Facebook right
it's like who are in competition
competition because you can see they're
still going to be the ego that the thing
that all the reasons we need vulnerable
transparency right all the ickiness that
like power and money and everything
brings up it's gonna exist it's gonna be
there but yeah I don't know Roy's going
to that but I like to Raymond it's the
same yeah it's that icky stuff that
doesn't get talked about that's actually
resisting the text merge right cuz
everybody's got their little attachments
I'm certainly do I'm heavily invested in
hollow chain I want all the chain to win
but I want to hold the chain the Loon
long before I was heavily invested but
you know but yeah it's always there it's
always there I think we do have a
coordination problem that I don't I
don't have any solutions for it just
because I you know you do see someone
says oh yeah so I want to create a you
know a Facebook alternative and there's
like 20 people working on that you know
we have two or three people trying to
build the same thing which isn't
necessarily bad but it just seems that
they're just not aware of each other and
then when they are then by the time
you're aware of each other you you have
such different concepts on how to
implement it that it's hard to switch
gears I'm with a group called the
canonical debate lab and I guess there's
probably about seven people on it now
and we each have our own debate software
so yeah although we're learning together
where we are in coopertition council
together so we meet once a week and we
talk about what's happening in each
other's projects and learn from each
other so we've started to find that but
it took us like four or five years so
we've each been working on this for five
years before we found each other finally
that's why it was very useful to have
this meeting yesterday and on Thursday
about nothing tools
that seems like for everyone who joins
the mapping group and at all that they
worked on and yeah this is my so it's
better I'm talking about
yeah now wait a minute rules add riyals
posting in the in the private chat about
sessions recorded yes we we have a right
now it's a private link with it and
making public so I'll send you the link
to the YouTube playlist and you could
look at them and I might oh I'll just
post it in-game being kissed anyone
wants to see it but I mean it gave me
projects but yeah it's um it's very
similar to this just with a focus in a
slightly different area but they're all
people trying to make the world a better
place as well so I could team's got more
space and Dougal it tell Jubilee and
Marcia's how all the chain solves both
the prophecy were talking but we call so
I'll learn about that I think like for
me and game be this this idea and it
happens a lot and it's just like sitting
with it and being like eventually it
will solve itself it's like oh yeah my
thing solves your thing and your thing
solved like but the fact they all exist
and everyone's fede not like up the same
pool of people and resources mean that
really none of them exist it's you know
that it's like yeah put your project on
my on my website and put your project
for my website but one of them will be
successful but the more its dissipated
everywhere and then really like none of
them are successful and that piece of it
is something we have to figure out
eventually from the bottom up or from
technology it facilitates it but it
can't be something that's like
commandeered through technology like I
say this is the one it's like it has to
emerge as the one which is hard it's
hard
ego aliens emotions yeah just you guy
think you can just unmute yourself okay
I'm still just trying to piece together
what's going on here so if everyone here
has kind of their own project that
they're working on
and right my right so far and all right
are these like private ventures are at
these like civic projects political
projects like I said um right
are these for-profit not-for-profit in
general all right all of the above the
theme that is consistent that they are
all trying to make the world a better
place and it is it's usually very game
be specific so try and be anti rivalries
resilience and those philosophies and
all of these are based on some kind of
technology I take it all of these
Jubilee it could you summarize like in
just a few words again sorry I I showed
up late but can you tell me it so it
sounds like you want 10,000 people and
$100,000 to do something right well if
you have 10,000 people you have $100,000
is the idea is 10,000 people put in ten
dollars you have 100,000 so it's about
finding 10,000 people who have a common
problem or starting with the problem
it's common for all of us like food but
finding yes
what is the process that it could look
like for 10,000 people to create
something like a food app that works for
them right that is it my food app I'm
selling into 10,000 I'm creating them
selling it to 10,000 people it's how do
you actually work through a process to
see does this thing we're creating meet
the need most of the needs most of the
time of these 10,000 and so that is what
what I am looking on is to find people
to talk about that process not looking
for 10,000 people if you handed me
10,000 people I wouldn't know what to do
with them it's having a smaller group of
people have the conversation of what
could it look like for 10,000 people to
have a conversation for 10,000 people to
have input in here are the features and
benefits we want in this out right
here's what I need it to have and then
using that pooled money to pay people to
actually work through game a model of
making the app right and like then we
own it together but people are actually
paid to do the actual
Oh Dean but the process like I was
involved in a community where we did a
similar process to create an intentional
community we decided everything we would
want on this land
well there's priorities we don't have a
swimming pool now well you know we
didn't really want to sort of boil
there's no trampoline for legit like we
went through every everything we would
want and then we list like what is the
order oh we need bathroom and then
kitchen and then you know we can get
downwards and there's a shop and a kid's
room in a team room but there's things
that made it in and things that didn't
based on finances based on how much we
care about it and that same process can
be used in technology where then I don't
have to create something and sell it to
you you're involved in the process of
creation so you already own it like in a
soul emotions level you want this to
succeed you want to use it and you're
putting ten dollars into the pool to
solve that does that make a little more
sense as to what I'm doing what you're
doing here what you thought all right
thanks and as first sorry as for what
we're doing here I feel like you came to
this not through game B do you know what
game B is good we've been involved in we
don't necessarily the came a is
basically history up to this point
capitalism all everything all of it
communism all of it and we know it's not
sustainable we know it's self
germinating so game B is the idea that
there's something we need a game B we
need a next thing that's gonna be
infinite but is an infinite game that is
Omni when that is anti rival risk for
the more people involved the more
benefit we all have and we all have AI
so in the game B space there's a lot of
people with projects a lot of people
with ideas on how we do that and their
piece of it and so together Tech and the
project's the Facebook projects for game
B is about bringing those project
holders together to find those Omni win
solutions from here where we are where
we're not willing to give up our
projects are not necessarily willing to
come together and collaborate on a new
project besides holding our projects and
doing the meta project of how can we
support each other right now it looks
like these calls in the Facebook group
we might create the technology that
actually does it or someone else will
and then we'll use it and create the
next thing
it's amazing how difficult it is Adriel
is not able there's a to add your
project to the together tech prototype
which is an AK and it's posted in the
game be Facebook group several times of
yes put your project on there so we can
coordinate it's the closest thing you
have at the moment
sorry view feeling of what all of our
projects are yes yeah and sorry for
cutting you off the continue that was
mean how do you share this information
there is a in the Facebook group yes did
you not come to yours yes that Facebook
group in there is that yes the URL that
is a good he drew all what's the URL you
type it in the comments and then we book
in the private check better so it's in
the private chat and you can copy and
paste it from there and I'm also gonna
post it in comments comments for other
people that we're talking about and put
it up on the screen and we're gonna make
that more visible it's kind of a
prototype but you know once again where
we're creating things that they already
exist but yeah but using nap just yeah
figure out what we need what we need it
isn't available in what RT already
exists my guess is they'll Colo chain
and double stack have something for this
this space as well but they don't exist
yet right and we're at the end of the
hour so we do this every Saturday we
have a roundtable at this time 9:00 9:00
a.m. Pacific Standard Time and then next
week we have this and we have a 2:00
p.m.
are we doing the 2:00 p.m. slot actually
there might be there might be two we're
definitely Aniston next week and then
there might also be the GPM oh no no I
think it would be better on I'll post it
I think it's better than verbal gotcha
that makes sense so yeah we do this
every Saturday and then Fridays we
switch back and forth between having a
board meeting for the meta project and
having an idea cafe which is people
bringing their projects and us and
during questions that from to show the
commonality of our projects right like
we all have to deal with marketing we
all have to deal with financing we all
have to deal with this like transparency
and vulnerability even if it's not like
every business has to deal with that
even if they don't have any idea they
have to deal with right so how do we so
we answering questions about it so next
week is actually a cafe which we have
yet to figure we have yet to decide on
the question I believe that we're
according to for yesterday we didn't
actually I think get around to it but
they'll be a question that's basically
together check us Fridays at noon
pacific standard times and 9:00 a.m. on
Saturdays to do the roundtables and then
how you find the links to come and
participate is the Facebook group game
be projects most of us are together or
the Facebook group groups together Tech
is the URL and I clearly butchered that
but does anyone have any closing
statements for the round table before we
say goodbye to YouTube and Facebook all
right how can I'd like to catch up and
maybe chat with y'all so you guys
everyone is here in the group easy to
find right and that Facebook group right
yeah participating in there so we'll see
what you post all right most of us are
following it and you can see the members
and friend any of them or I mean I can't
guarantee they'll friend you back but I
but I will for the project raising
understand
that's one our hot seat thing to be
happening because something I was
working on these lines discussed and I
use and like some feedback about knowing
English makes any sense so yeah so we
were doing solution Racing's on
Saturdays they were during this time
period and we've removed that because
we're not doing this but anyone can put
up in the game
that Facebook group a project phrasing
so pick a time put it up say here's what
I want to concentrate on here's what I'm
doing I would love people to come and
and you know give me an hour of their
time to concentrate on it it's a little
bit of that transparent vulnerability we
don't know if it's gonna work or not we
don't know whether people are gonna show
up but that is is right now that that is
is something we want to offer but how we
offer that in that space without taking
up the same hour every week and
committing to it to have someone say yes
I'm available at next time and then have
people people come on so you're more
than welcome to post in the Facebook
group that you want a project raising
what you wanted on the time or you can
do a doodle poll if you have several
times that you want it Pacific Saturday
is probably a good time cause we have
used that that's open right now but but
any fix some bugs
so if ya put it on for 2:00 p.m. next
Saturday would be perfect and then like
some of us will probably be there and
then other people might be there I mean
one of us will be either angel or I will
be there during the stream yard part of
it for you
I'll be here he's not right comment real
quick about this whole 10,000 people it
sounds like you want an army and it
costs money to have an army now you have
to pay a lot of money for a standing
army and so unless you have an immediate
usually yeah you yeah you might not
actually it's it's not efficient to have
a standing army usually armies I mean
unless you are a big state and you have
a big budgets no one er they are
standing army in no way in fact they're
they're like yeah yeah no they're not a
standing army we're not feeding them and
clothing them and housing them so that
they're on standby so they can work on
this that's the point is the 10,000
people aren't working on it it's five
people working on it it's ten people
working on it but it's 10,000 people
give you their input 10,000 people
voting for you what I want in that right
so they're feeding clothing themselves
and how do we create the apps that we
can feed and clothe ourselves for
or that is what they're getting out of
it they're getting that like they don't
need to hand themselves over to their
government to put their lives on the
line for their cut for their country
their hey how much of this do I want to
give myself and is it an hour a month
it's an hour a day it's their choice how
much they want to give except when we
need full-time coders then we need to
pay them so it's that's the idea the
10,000 isn't marching to solve the
problem it's 10,000 people putting their
input in and putting 10 dollars in from
their work that they do in the real you
know in-game a or maybe remember they're
doing their work and then having a say
in it and then there's a much time your
group probably that's involved in more
of a full-time full-time job is that
answer we can have a question definitely
reach out if you have more questions and
I can answer them where we can have a
video chat ourselves about it I'm
totally done with that but it's been an
hour so let's say goodbye to YouTube and
Facebook and I have to go see what my
kids been up to in the last hour